A Finding Aid to the Anna Coleman Ladd Papers, 1881-1950, in the Archives of American Art AAA.laddanna
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1889-1942; Series 9; 0.5 Linear feet Box 3, 6, OV 7
  - Oversized Printed Material, 1920 (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 3, F29, 40, 65
  - Oversized World War I Posters, 1918 (Box OV 7)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 3, F40
- Photographs, 1881-1932; Series 10; 0.8 Linear feet Box 4-6, MGP 1
  Photographs are of Anna Coleman Ladd, her family, friends, colleagues, her summer studio at Beverly Farms, Manchester, Massachusetts, her art work, and the art work of others. There is an autographed photo of Italian poet Giosuè Carducci, who won the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1906. Photographs of art work include an image of Ladd's work autographed by Bela Lyon Pratt. There is also a photograph of sculptor John Ettl in his studio. Additional photographs are found in Scrapbooks and Ladd's file on her portrait masks.
  This series has been partially scanned. Negatives have not been scanned. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Anna Coleman Ladd as a Child, 1881-circa 1890 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Anna Coleman Ladd as a Young Woman, 1900-circa 1906 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Anna Coleman Ladd with Artwork, circa 1909-circa 1930 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Anna Coleman Ladd in Uniform and Snapshots, circa 1914-circa 1920 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Anna Coleman Ladd with Friends, circa 1900-circa 1920 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Maynard Ladd, circa 1900-1918 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wedding, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ladd Family, 1897-1920 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1900-1932 (Box 4, Folder 9-12)
  - Houses, circa 1905 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Arden" Summer Studio, circa 1910 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Artist's Model, circa 1910 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Portrait Busts of Females, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Portrait Busts of Males, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sculpture of Female Figures, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
  - Sculpture of Male Figures, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sculpture of Religious Figures, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Sculpture of Angels, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sculpture of Soldiers and Warriors, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sculpture of Putti and Nymphs, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sculpture of Miscellaneous Figure Groups, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sculpture for a Sundial and Birdbaths, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fountain Sculpture, "Youth with the Blue Bird,", circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fountain Sculpture, "Triton Babies,", circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fountain Sculpture, "Ocean and Sail,", circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fountain Sculpture, "Wind and Spray,", circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fountain Sculpture, Unidentified, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Relief Sculpture, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Sculpture, circa 1920s (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Art Work by Others, 1909-circa 1920 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Installations, circa 1920 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Buildings, circa 1920 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1910; 3 Glass negatives (Box MGP 1)
  - Oversized Photographs, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 4, F6, 20, 21 and Box 5, F7